<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Media Centre | Premier of Victoria</title><link>https://www.premier.vic.gov.au/media-centre</link><description>Posts from the Victorian State Government's media centre</description><language>en-AU</language><copyright>Copyright State Government of Victoria</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 17:27:12 +1100</lastBuildDate><generator>Scrapy 2.4.1</generator><item><title>Resources Sector Rocks On With More Growth</title><link>http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/resources-sector-rocks-more-growth</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Victoria’s resources sector has continued its strong growth with high demand to meet the Andrews Labor Government’s big infrastructure agenda delivering record production and more jobs across the state.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Minister for Resources Jaclyn Symes updated Parliament today on the sector’s continued strong performance in minerals exploration expenditure and quarry production. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Earth Resources Regulation 2019-20 Annual Statistical Report&lt;/em&gt; reveals that quarry production has now grown by twenty-five per cent over the last six years – providing over sixty-three million tonnes of sand, rock and gravel last financial year to help deliver new housing and infrastructure development.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Minerals exploration spending in Victoria has grown – according to Australian Bureau of Statistics data expenditure increased by a third in 2019-20 compared to the previous year. Over the same period, gold mining expenditure also increased by a third and gold production by nearly forty per cent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;World-leading geoscience has underpinned this minerals boom. The Geological Survey of Victoria estimates that around 75 million ounces of gold is yet to be found. The news of Victoria’s exploration and mining potential has sparked an increase in minerals licensing, total applications for 2019-20 up seventy-five per cent to 154. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This track record of growth has raised Victoria’s profile globally as a hub for resources production. Melbourne will again be on show when it hosts the 2021 International Mining and Resources Conference (IMARC), Australia’s largest annual mining and resources event. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;IMARC 2021 will take place from 25 to 27 October at the Melbourne Showgrounds, allowing organisers to include an outdoor exhibition space into its program for the first time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;An extra $1.1 million was provided in the recent &lt;em&gt;Victorian Budget 2020/21&lt;/em&gt; to process the unprecedented number of applications and ensure the sector can ramp up its works to help the state’s economic recovery.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Earth Resources Regulation has undertaken significant reform through the actions identified in &lt;em&gt;Getting the Groundwork Right: Better regulation of mines and quarries &lt;/em&gt;report. Action has been taken to support the growth of the sector with safeguards in place to better protect public safety and the environment.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Minister for Resources Jaclyn Symes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Minerals and quarry products play an essential role in our everyday lives – they make up the houses we live in, the train tracks we ride on, and the computers we work from. Our resources sector helps us all.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“The resources sector has kept going all throughout this pandemic – supporting jobs and our everyday needs. IMARC 2021 will be a fantastic chance for those businesses to reconnect and celebrate this continuing, strong success.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>State Government of Victoria</author><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/resources-sector-rocks-more-growth</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 15:30:11 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Historic Laws Passed To Decriminalise Public Drunkenness</title><link>http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/historic-laws-passed-decriminalise-public-drunkenness</link><description>&lt;p&gt;People who are drunk in public will get the health support and help they need with laws to decriminalise public drunkenness passing Parliament today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Summary Offences Amendment (Decriminalisation of Public Drunkenness) Bill 2020&lt;/em&gt; will save lives by ensuring no one can be locked in a police cell just for being drunk in public. It paves the way for public drunkenness to be treated as a health issue, not a crime.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;These laws have been informed by Aboriginal communities and health experts – who have advocated for this reform for decades – and enable the Government to move to culturally safe and appropriate model that prioritises the health and safety of individuals who are intoxicated in public, as well as the broader community.         &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This will include&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; more&lt;/span&gt; outreach services&lt;span&gt;, training for first responders and new sobering up services &lt;/span&gt;–&lt;span&gt; making sure people are transported to a safe place where they can receive support if they need it. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Bill builds on three decades of work and activism,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; including &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;key recommendations from the Royal Commission into Aboriginal Deaths in Custody, and the Coronial Inquest into the tragic death of Tanya Day. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the next two years, the Government will continue to work closely with Aboriginal communities, health experts and key stakeholders – including Victoria Police – to design, trial and refine the public health model and develop local solutions that are safe and effective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;These reforms were&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; developed following extensive consultation to ensure they strike the right balance between protection of people who are intoxicated and community safety. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government is currently considering trial site locations in line with advice provided by an Expert Reference Group report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Attorney-General Jaclyn Symes      &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Today we have delivered a reform that is long overdue – public drunkenness laws have caused too much pain for too many and we acknowledge everyone who has fought tirelessly for this change.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We’ll continue to work closely with Aboriginal communities, health experts and other stakeholders, including police to establish a health model &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;that focuses on support and safety, not punishment.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US"&gt;Quote attributable to Minister for Aboriginal Affairs Gabrielle Williams&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We have worked with and listened to the Aboriginal community to deliver real change. These reforms will save lives and provide fair and culturally appropriate care – that's the right thing to do.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US"&gt;Quote attributable to Minister for Health Martin Foley   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US"&gt;“This important change wraps a culturally appropriate health response around vulnerable people who are drunk in public, giving them the immediate help they need.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>State Government of Victoria</author><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/historic-laws-passed-decriminalise-public-drunkenness</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 17:27:55 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>St Kilda Penguin Parade Re-Opens To Visitors</title><link>http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/st-kilda-penguin-parade-re-opens-visitors</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Victorians can once again watch the penguins on parade with the re-opening of the St Kilda Pier Breakwater – one of Melbourne’s top tourist attractions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister for Energy, Environment and Climate Change Lily D’Ambrosio joined Member for Albert Park Martin Foley and Member for Southern Metropolitan Nina Taylor on the opening night to watch hundreds of Little Penguins make their nightly waddle home to shore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was the first time the Breakwater has been open to visitors since its closure last year, with the attraction now boasting three scheduled viewings an evening and roaming Penguin Rangers to ensure COVIDSafe arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The St Kilda Pier Breakwater is home to up to 1,400 Little Penguins and has become one of Melbourne’s most popular tourist hotspots, previously drawing crowds of up to 3,000 people a night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The five new Penguin Rangers and three scheduled viewings – limited to 30 people per viewing based on current COVIDSafe arrangements – means the attraction can once again resume safely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tours to see the penguin colony are free, but tickets must be pre-booked on the Parks Victoria website at &lt;a href="http://www.parks.vic.gov.au/places-to-see/parks/st-kilda-pier-and-breakwater/attractions/little-penguins" data-print-url="http://www.parks.vic.gov.au/places-to-see/parks/st-kilda-pier-and-breakwater/attractions/little-penguins" class="rpl-link rpl-text-link"&gt;&lt;span class="rpl-link__inner"&gt;&lt;span class="rpl-text-label"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!----&gt; &lt;span class="rpl-text-icon__group"&gt;parks.vic.gov.au/places-to-see&lt;svg viewbox="0 0 14 14" aria-hidden="true" overflow="visible" class="rpl-icon rpl-icon--external_link rpl-icon--color_primary rpl-text-icon--after" style="width:14px;height:14px;"&gt;&lt;path d="M14 1.54v11.062C14 13.3 13.3 14 12.46 14H1.54C.7 14 0 13.3 0 12.46V1.54C0 .7.7 0 1.54 0h11.062C13.3 0 14 .7 14 1.54zm-2.8.42H7.7c-.56 0-.981.84-.419 1.259l.98.98-6.16 6.16a.428.428 0 000 .563l.977.976c.14.141.422.141.563 0l6.16-6.16.98.98c.418.563 1.258.141 1.258-.417V2.8c0-.422-.418-.84-.84-.84z"&gt;&lt;/path&gt; &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Tours will run nightly from February to April 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Originally built for as a sailing harbour for the 1956 Melbourne Olympics, a colony of Little Penguins moved in at the Breakwater once the athletes departed, roosting in the rocks after a long day’s fishing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With their unique blue feathers, Little Penguins are the world’s smallest penguin species, about the height of a football and weighing around 1 kilogram each.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike their country cousins at Phillip Island, Little Penguins have exceptionally long breeding seasons due to the high availability of the penguin’s favourite foods, like pilchards and anchovies, in Port Phillip Bay. They are doubly fat and fluffy at the moment – the end of the breeding season – as they prepare to moult.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Minister for Energy, Environment and Climate Change Lily D’Ambrosio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Our COVIDSafe measures will ensure as many people as possible can enjoy seeing the penguins each evening throughout the summer, as safely as possible.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I’m thrilled that St Kilda’s cutest residents will once again be open for visitors with the help of Parks Victoria rangers and Earthcare volunteers – they deserve an adoring (and respectful) audience.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quote attributable to Member for Albert Park Martin Foley&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The Little Penguin colony at St Kilda is one of Melbourne’s most special and iconic sights – these new measures will not only help crowds be COVIDSafe but also ensure the penguins are disturbed as little as possible.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quote attributable to Member for Southern Metropolitan Nina Taylor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“These penguins have been a part of the landscape at the St Kilda Pier Breakwater for decades and it is fantastic we can once again enjoy the sight of these beautiful animals waddling to shore.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>State Government of Victoria</author><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/st-kilda-penguin-parade-re-opens-visitors</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 07:25:37 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Statement From The Premier</title><link>http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/statement-premier-87</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Minister for Police and Emergency Services and Minister for Water, Lisa Neville, will take a three month leave of absence from today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms Neville was recently admitted to hospital as a result of complications associated with a previously diagnosed chronic auto-immune disorder, Crohn's disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She has received medical advice confirming she will not be able to return to work this week as intended, and will require a period of further treatment and recovery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During this period, her portfolio responsibilities will be covered through the following acting arrangements:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Victorian Government, I’d like to extend my warmest wishes to Lisa for her recovery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She is a highly valued, relentlessly dedicated member of our team. She has our full support in taking the time to focus on her recovery, and we look forward to welcoming her back as soon as her health allows.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>State Government of Victoria</author><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/statement-premier-87</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 15:41:59 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Innovation Stems From Women On Resources Boards  </title><link>http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/innovation-stems-women-resources-boards</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Andrews Labor Government is helping more women into leadership positions in the resources industry, with the latest recipients of the Women on Boards Scholarship program announced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister for Resources Jaclyn Symes today congratulated the three recipients on being accepted in the second round of the program, which aims to increase the number of women with Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics (STEM) knowledge sitting on mining and resources boards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recipients of the Women on Boards Scholarship are Laura Spelbrink, Senior Exploration Geologist at Sandfire Resources; Nerilee Rockman, Vice President Legal, Environment &amp;amp; Supply Chain at AngloGold Ashanti Australia; and Amy Lamb, Head of Processing at MMG.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The program is part of the Prospects Partnership between the Government and the Australasian Institute of Mining and Metallurgy (AusIMM), the peak body representing resources sector professionals. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Prospects Partnership focuses on retaining women with science and technical backgrounds in the resources sector and is part of &lt;em&gt;State of Discovery&lt;/em&gt;, Victoria’s Minerals Resources Strategy released in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Research shows diverse boards result in better outcomes and greater innovation. While the number of women on boards within the resources sector is increasing, women with technical industry skills remain underrepresented.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a boom in minerals exploration, record high-grade gold production and the orderly restart of onshore conventional gas from July 2021, the leadership opportunities for women across the sector are promising.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The September 2020 quarter saw a 31 per cent increase in year-on-year mineral exploration expenditure compared to the September 2019 quarter. Since September 2016, the average quarterly mineral exploration expenditure growth in Victoria has been 10 per cent— twice the average quarterly growth of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Minister for Resources Jaclyn Symes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Broadening the diversity on boards means more views and experiences have a voice at the table, which can only improve our booming resources sector. Congratulations to the recipients – I can’t wait to see what they achieve.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“It’s programs like this scholarship that encourage more women to consider the resources industry as a career path.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quote attributable to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Senior Exploration Geologist at Sandfire Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laura Spelbrink&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“For many women, the path to senior leadership can be difficult to navigate and programs such as this equip participants with the skills, confidence and visibility to take a seat at the table.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quote attributable to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Head of Processing at MMG&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Amy Lamb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Programs like this really help increase company diversity and promote innovation and growth.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quote attributable to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VP Legal, Environment &amp;amp; Supply Chain at AngloGold Ashanti Australia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Nerilee Rockman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;“I am very grateful to the AusIMM and the Victorian Government for making such a scholarship available and deepening the pool of board-ready women, both in in the mining sector and more generally.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>State Government of Victoria</author><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/innovation-stems-women-resources-boards</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 10:24:39 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Statement From Lisa Neville</title><link>http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/statement-lisa-neville-0</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I was admitted to hospital as a result of complications associated with Crohn’s disease, a disease I have been living with for 32 years. This condition is an auto-immune disease which I have successfully managed throughout my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months I had been managing the most recent episode from home, however my condition progressively worsened and required hospitalisation last week. I remain in hospital currently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the course of the past week in hospital the seriousness of these complications and the impact on my health has become more evident.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following extensive treatment this week, and after consultation with health professionals who have formed the view I cannot return to work as planned, I will be taking a leave of absence for 3 months for further treatment and recovery. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crohn’s is a chronic disease. Many people in the community live with this condition, and to date I have successfully managed the effects of it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However the current episode is the worst I have been confronted with. The clear advice from my doctors is if I don’t take this period of rest and recovery I will be faced with major bowel surgery and risk long term consequences to the quality and length of my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love my job and remain passionately committed to it. Across the portfolios of Water and Police and Emergency Services I have had the honour of working with dedicated individuals who serve and protect the interests of the Victorian community. My love for the community of the Bellarine Peninsula and working hard to deliver for all of my constituents remains as strong as it was when I was first elected. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am working with my doctors on my recovery and will be guided by their advice on when my physical health can allow me to return to work, which at this stage they believe will be in 3 months time. I also ask for privacy during this time as I focus solely on my health and wellbeing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to thank the health professionals who have provided such expert care and advice to me, and who will continue to guide my recovery and return to work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to acknowledge and thank my cabinet and caucus colleagues for supporting me to take the time I need to make a full recovery. Thank you also to the many friends who have wished me well during this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>State Government of Victoria</author><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/statement-lisa-neville-0</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 15:48:03 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Support For Businesses Impacted By Circuit Breaker Action</title><link>http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/support-businesses-impacted-circuit-breaker-action</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New support has been announced for small businesses, including sole traders, most impacted by the coronavirus circuit-breaker action – with hospitality, tourism, events and creative industries operators to benefit from grants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New $200 vouchers for travel in regional Victoria and Melbourne will further bolster tourism businesses and workers, while licenced venues and accommodation businesses will receive dedicated new assistance as vibrancy returns to our night-time and visitor economies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The $143 million Circuit Breaker Support Package is expected to help more than 50,000 Victorian businesses – including restaurants, florists, confectioners, hairdressers, accommodation providers, musicians and performers – who incurred costs such as the loss of perishable goods, cancelled gigs and foregone trading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The package contains four initiatives targeted at businesses, including small and micro businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new $92 million Business Costs Assistance Program will offer grants of $2,000 for eligible employing and non-employing businesses in the hospitality, food wholesaling, tourism, events and selected retail industries. Businesses with an annual payroll of  up to $3 million will be eligible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A $24.9 million injection to the Licensed Hospitality Venue Fund will give previous recipients of this grant an automatic one-off $3,000 per premises payment. More than $165 million has already been paid to about 7,500 businesses through this fund.    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Victorian Accommodation Support Program recognises the impact of cancellations on regional and metropolitan accommodation providers through a $16.2 million commitment. Accommodation providers who had 10 or fewer cancellations can apply for $2,250 per business while providers with more than 10 booking cancellations can apply for $4,500 per business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Building on the success of the Regional Travel Voucher Scheme, a further $10 million will expand the scheme to include a new Melbourne Travel Voucher Scheme, offering 40,000 vouchers for $200 for travel in greater Melbourne, and an additional 10,000 vouchers to support travel in regional Victoria.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Regional Travel Voucher Scheme and Melbourne Travel Voucher Scheme now spans 200,000 vouchers for eligible Victorians, providing a vital boost to the tourism sector as the state resumes its recovery.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Andrews Labor Government has provided more than $6 billion in direct economic support for businesses and workers to help them get through the pandemic and recover strongly, including $2.6 billion alone in Business Support Fund grants to 134,000 businesses – more than half of all employing businesses in Victoria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information about the Circuit Breaker Support Package is available at &lt;a href="http://www.business.vic.gov.au/" data-print-url="http://www.business.vic.gov.au/" class="rpl-link rpl-text-link"&gt;&lt;span class="rpl-link__inner"&gt;&lt;span class="rpl-text-label"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!----&gt; &lt;span class="rpl-text-icon__group"&gt;business.vic.gov.au&lt;svg viewbox="0 0 14 14" aria-hidden="true" overflow="visible" class="rpl-icon rpl-icon--external_link rpl-icon--color_primary rpl-text-icon--after" style="width:14px;height:14px;"&gt;&lt;path d="M14 1.54v11.062C14 13.3 13.3 14 12.46 14H1.54C.7 14 0 13.3 0 12.46V1.54C0 .7.7 0 1.54 0h11.062C13.3 0 14 .7 14 1.54zm-2.8.42H7.7c-.56 0-.981.84-.419 1.259l.98.98-6.16 6.16a.428.428 0 000 .563l.977.976c.14.141.422.141.563 0l6.16-6.16.98.98c.418.563 1.258.141 1.258-.417V2.8c0-.422-.418-.84-.84-.84z"&gt;&lt;/path&gt; &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quote attributable to Minister for Industry Support and Recovery Martin Pakula&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Victorian businesses played their part in the circuit breaker action and this package recognises that the impact for many was severe.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quote attributable to Minister for Small Business Jaala Pulford&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We know it hurt businesses to shut their doors, but the long-term benefits are clear. A temporary pause has meant businesses can now get on with their rebuilding – with our full support.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>State Government of Victoria</author><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/support-businesses-impacted-circuit-breaker-action</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 07:32:35 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>High-Risk Workers To Receive First Vaccine In Victoria</title><link>http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/high-risk-workers-receive-first-vaccine-victoria</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Workers most likely to come into direct contact with a suspected coronavirus (COVID-19) case will be the first Victorians vaccinated under the Commonwealth’s COVID-19 vaccination program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following arrival of the vaccine, from Monday, trained Victorian health professionals will start delivering doses of the Pfizer vaccine to hotel quarantine and health hotel workers, airport and port workers, high-risk frontline health staff and public sector residential aged care staff and residents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public health services operating hospital vaccination ‘hubs’ will administer the Pfizer vaccines at dedicated hospital facilities, hotel quarantine settings, Melbourne Airport, or through mobile outreach teams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Austin Health, Monash Health and Western Health hubs will deliver the initial vaccines to Victoria’s most at-risk workers. Alfred Health will also work with the Monash Health hub to deliver vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hubs will deliver the vaccine to public sector residential aged care patients and workers, with the Commonwealth responsible for providing the vaccine to residents and workers in private sector aged care and disability care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Barwon Health hub will begin its public sector residential aged care program from next week, trialling an outreach model to be implemented across regional Victoria. Barwon Health will also vaccinate port of entry workers in Portland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hubs at Albury-Wodonga Health, Ballarat Health Services, Bendigo Health, Goulburn Valley Health, and Latrobe Regional Hospital will begin operating in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Commonwealth has allocated 12,000 initial doses of the Pfizer vaccine for use at the hospital vaccination hubs in the first week of the program, with the Commonwealth set to provide 59,000 doses of the vaccine to Victoria over the first four weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pfizer vaccine was the first COVID-19 vaccine to receive Commonwealth regulatory approval from the TGA in Australia. It meets high safety, efficacy and quality standards. Two doses of the vaccine will be provided at least three weeks apart. The vaccine must be stored and transported at -70°C.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The AstraZeneca vaccine was approved by the TGA on 16 February. The first doses of this vaccine are expected to be available for use in March. As Victoria receives increased vaccine supplies of both the Pfizer and AstraZeneca vaccines, the rollout will progress through to phase 1b, 2a and 2b priority groups. Victoria continues to work with the Commonwealth on options for delivery of these doses, such as more suburban and regional hubs, community- based settings and outreach models. More information about additional vaccination centres will provided over the coming weeks, as details are confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Minister for Health Martin Foley &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Our priority is to support the Commonwealth to make sure that the vaccine is administered to workers at the highest risk of contracting COVID-19 as quickly and safely possible.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Whether they work in hotel quarantine, at the airport, or a specialist COVID ward – we need to keep Victorians most at risk of infection safe, while they continue to keep Victorians safe.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>State Government of Victoria</author><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/high-risk-workers-receive-first-vaccine-victoria</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 07:45:40 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lara Station Upgrades To Get Underway </title><link>http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/lara-station-upgrades-get-underway</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!----&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister for Public Transport&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Ben Carroll&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;said the first stage of the program of works were part of the government’s $328.4 million investment in critical public transport and roads maintenance and upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lara is one of 16 key stations, along with North Geelong and North Shore stations, to receive a share in a $24 million package to support jobs and deliver improved facilities for passengers along the Geelong corridor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The works at Lara Station will be rolled out in stages and the initial works will involve a refurbishment of the station waiting room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A team of six contractors will be working on site to deliver a fresh coat of paint for the waiting room and new carpet, to help make the precinct more inviting and comfortable for passengers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!----&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!----&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crews will continue to follow strict &lt;span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US"&gt;protocols as set out by the Department of Health and Human Services on work sites to protect the health and safety of workers and the community during the works.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Minister for Public Transport Ben Carroll&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“These important projects are not only delivering much needed upgrades – but supporting regional communities as we continue to rebuild and recover from the global pandemic.”  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We continue to see significant growth right along the Geelong line so we’re delivering upgrades and improvements that passengers have asked for to help improve their travel experience.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to the Member for Lara John Eren  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It’s wonderful to see that three stations along the Geelong line will benefit from this funding to provide a more comfortable, accessible and safer journey for passengers.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It’s important we look after our station precincts so they continue to serve the needs of passengers and keep our local economy moving as we recover from the coronavirus pandemic.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>State Government of Victoria</author><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.premier.vic.gov.au/lara-station-upgrades-get-underway</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:48:14 +1100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>